Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/piyush-dangaich-90103524 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

R

VBA

SQL

Piyush Dangaich

Director, Enterprise Sales at Saarthi.ai | Vernacular Conversational Al

Bengaluru

Summary

Seasoned Consultant with more than 5 years of experience and strong track record of performance in translating business needs into meaningful and easily consumable data driven analysis. Engaging with clients to understand various business challenges which can be resolved with power of AI and in building customer acquisition, EMOB, lifecycle, cross-sell and retention strategies applying various concepts of statistics, advanced analytics and Artificial Intelligence thereby driving effective business decisions.

Experience

Saarthi.ai Enterprise Sales Director April 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months) Bengaluru Area, India

Joined Saarthi.ai bringing in more than 5 years of strong data science consulting and hands-on experience of working on analytical problems across multiple domains and geographies.

Saarthi.ai is an AI startup which has built strong Native Spoken Language Understanding stack in more than 22 languages so far. Saarthi.ai provides developer platform to Enterprises for easy development of E2E Virtual Assistant and deploy in multiple channels and languages.

The Tech-Sales role gives me a great opportunity to showcase Saarthi's technological sophistication and strong solution development capability to Enterprises around the globe.

Primary responsibility at Saarthi.ai:

- Build and develop strong business relationship with existing clients & prospects along with project planning
- Develop Road-map for Enterprises to realise power of SMART Conversational Agents in incremental phases

Currently, also responsible for project management and actively participating in project execution.

Fractal Analytics 5 years 3 months

Senior Consultant March 2017 - March 2019 (2 years 1 month)

Bengaluru Area, India

Client facing role working with a new client, one of the biggest technology company across the globe, with a responsibility of building strong relationship by providing analytical sophistication required by the Client for addressing major business challenges.

- Responsible for panning and supporting the Account growth strategies
- Conducted analysis and provided analytics support across various business arms like Paid Ad platform, Free Ad platform, Mobile App optimisation. Also, provided effective Sales Rep assistance by providing market insights on various company products
- In a fast growing team in multiple region, played a pivotal role in mentoring new joinees across different location and onboard them to the Client environment, system and platforms

Consultant

October 2016 - February 2017 (5 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Supported a major Healthcare distributor of US by applying Advanced analytics and ML techniques to generate powerful insights and develop growth strategies.

- Developed a Pricing recommendation tool to assist Sales Reps. The tool takes into consideration Past engagement and Future potential of various customer and accordingly Customer-SKU level pricing recommendation is provided
- Conducted Driver analysis to understand drivers and drainers of % Profit . The worked involved harmonisation of Big data from various sources like sales, distribution, stock, demand forecast, etc., and clustering to group together similar performing SKU's and assessment of drivers and drainers at Cluster level

Consultant

April 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 6 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Client facing role in Banking domain, responsible for strong communication during project planning and data requirement phases.

- Developed a Credit card Over-limit Transaction Authentication model for a major Bank in India. The model provides customer level pre-approved size of over limit transactions taking into consideration the long-term and short-term profit and loss factors.
- Generated powerful insights and developed strategies for various stages in Customer Lifecycle like Acquisition, On-boarding, Engagement and Attrition.
- Developed customer 360 Portfolio Management tool to provide client easy access to various type of information regarding their customer base
- Utilised Customer 360 information and developed customer segmentation along with segment level strategies to improve various marketing campaign effectiveness
- Applied supervised ML techniques to identify attrition in early stages

Analyst

January 2014 - March 2015 (1 year 3 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Worked for multiple clients in BFSI domain with following responsibilities:

- Understand reasons for cross-border transaction decline and recommend areas to improve approval rate
- Understand the readiness of various markets for Electronic transactions and recommend development strategies to a major payment technology company
- Identify and target for up-selling Commercial cards to likely consumer card customers

Learnt and worked on multiple tools/techniques like:

Excel, PowerPoint, SAS, R, Python, Xcelcius, VBA, Tableau, SpotFire, QlikView, Advanced statistical concepts, multiple ML techniques.

Jindal Steel & Power Ltd.

One of the fastest growing company in steel sector July 2013 - January 2014 (7 months)

Worked as a Graduate Engineering Trainee in E&I department under Plate Mill Section. Involved in planning and execution of HTL project which is India's second Heat Treatment Leveller.

Page 3 of 4

Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee

Bachelor's Degree, Electrical Engineering · (2009 - 2013)